Arun Kumar A



Mobile: +91 9442990133 E-mail: arunjamps@gmail.com

Executive Summary

Highly motivated HSE Assistant Manager with over 6 years of experience, dedicated to Occupational Health and Safety. Certified and trained professional with extensive knowledge of safety procedures, applicable codes. Effective at quickly assessing situations and responding with effective solutions. Solid reputation for superior performance, accuracy, and decision making ability.

Key Result Areas

- Training program implementation
- Time & Resource Allocation
- Hazard identification Risk Assessment

- Facility & Equipment
- Investigations & Reporting
- Toolbox talks

Professional Experience

SODEXO FACILITY MANAGEMENT SERVICE INDIA PVT LTD

POSITION: ASSISTANT MANAGER HSE - TAMILNADU & PONDY

DURATION: NOV 2014 TO TILL DATE

SAMSUNG INDIA ELCTRONICS PVT LTD, CHENNAI

POSITION: EHS EXECUTIVE

DURATION: JANUARY 2014 TO NOVEMBER 2014

• MACLELLAN INTEGRATED SERVICE INDIA PVT LTD.

POSITION: SAFETY OFFICER.

CLIENT: NOKIA INDIA.

DURATION: DECEMBER 2012 TO JANUARY 2014

KOTEC AUTOMOTIVE SERVICE INDIA (P) LTD, CHENNAI.

POSITION: SAFETY OFFICER.

CLIENT: FORD INDIA,

FROM: AUGUST 2011 TO DECEMBER 2012

Job Responsibilities:

- Coordination for various audit such as OHSAS 18001, ISO 14001, Fire prevention Survey (NFPA Standard) & ISO 9001.
- Conduction QHSE Audits based on OHSAS Standard in all my respective sites regularly and sharing the report to the site team and reviewing the CAPA.
- Preparing Tool Box Talk and circulated to all sites.
- Conduction training to all the site employees and managers.
- Strong knowledge of safety procedure (OSHAS standards).
- Wide experience in the field of managing safety aspects in Facility Management.
- Experienced in fire prevention, firefighting and safety procedures.
- Maintained all safety procedures and norms efficiently.
- Implemented safety measures & effective strategies to reduce risks and hence improved safety.
- Performed with group members to build up their headship and skills prospective.
- Drive, maintain and promote a safety conscious culture throughout our client facilities.
- Manage accident / incident cases as well as corrective / preventive action and reporting.
- Manage and maintain Accident Rate Statistics and report results to the management team.
- Identify and anticipate environmental, health, safety concerns / hazards and implement solutions.
- Conduct EHS related training of associates and management to ensure compliance with legal, system and customer requirements.
- Thorough knowledge on EHS legal requirement.
- To increase health and safety awareness at all levels within the organization.
- Evaluate safety concepts and coordinate risk and hazard analysis as well as reviews.
- To respond to employees, safety concerns.
- Involved in incident / accident investigation.

Academic Credentials

- Advance Diploma in Fire and Industrial Safety Management (White Cross Educational Institution)
- Bachelor of Computer Science (Yadava College Madurai)

Trainings & Certifications

OHSAS 18001:2007 Internal Auditor (DNV – GL)

- Occupational Safety (SITRUST Siemens)
- Fire Safety Certificate (Usha Fire)
- First Aid Certificate (St. John's Ambulance)

Computer Skills

Windows OS, Microsoft Office, Power point, Internet, and email.

Personal Dossier

Date of Birth : 20/09/1990 Passport No : J2723360 Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English and Tamil.

Permanent Address : No 46, Thiruvengadam Nagar, Poonamalle, Chennai.